Saving the world before bedtime!
The Powerpuff Girls Movie is a animation, action,
family film directed by Craig McCracken.
After destroying the city of Townsville in a game of tag, a trio of superpowered little girls
must redeem themselves by stopping a vengeful monkey's plot for world domination.
Blossom (voice), played by Cathy Cavadini.
Bubbles (voice), played by Tara Strong.
Buttercup (voice), played by E. G. Daily.
Mojo Jojo (voice), played by Roger L. Jackson.
Professor Utonium (voice), played by Tom Kane.
Mayor / Narrator / Ka-Ching Ka-Ching (voice), played by Tom Kenny.
The Powerpuff Girls Movie is a 2002 American animated
superhero comedy film based on the television series.
It was directed by series creator Craig McCracken, and co-written by McCracken, Charlie Bean, Lauren Faust, Paul
Rudish, and Don Shank, and features the regular television cast of Cathy Cavadini, Tara Strong, E.
Daily, Roger L.
Jackson, Tom Kane, Tom Kenny, Jennifer Hale, and Jennifer Martin.
Serving as an origin story of the titular characters, the film follows the newly created girls as they become
ostracized for inadvertently destroying Townsville and assisting in Mojo Jojo's plot for world domination.
Series composer James L.
Venable wrote the film's music score.
Produced by Cartoon Network Studios as its first theatrical film, The Powerpuff
Girls Movie was released in theaters on July 3, 2002, by Warner Bros.
The film received generally positive reviews from critics, and was a box-office disappointment, earning
$16 million on a budget of $11 million, which was partly blamed on a crowded marketplace.
The film explores themes of martial arts,
experiment, professor, superhero, cartoon.